Finding Aid for Fred S. Dunham paper, 1903-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred S. Dunham papers 1903-1970
Dunham, Fred Sylvester.
2 linear feet
861094 Aa 2
Professor of Latin in the School of Education at the University of Michigan; correspondence; student notebooks, topical files, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Robert Holbrook (donor no. 6519 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred Sylvester Dunham was born in Bennetsburg, N.Y., in 1881. He received both his bachelor's degree (1906) and master's degree (1907) from the University of Michigan. Prior to that, in 1902-1903, he had been principal of Maplehurst Union School in Hinsdale, N.Y. He had also taught at the Washington and Jefferson Academy and Shaker High School. In his career, Dunham was a professor of Latin at the University of Michigan. He was also head of the Latin department at the now dissolved University High School in the School of Education. Dunham was a member of the American Classical League, the American Philological Association, the Classical Association Middle West and South, and Phi Delta Kappa. He had extensively published on the subject of Latin instruction. He died April 22, 1970.
The Fred S. Dunham collection includes professional correspondence and notes taken while a student at the University of Michigan, 1903-1907, in classes taught by Francis W. Kelsey, Walter Dennison, Robert M. Wenley, Joseph Drake, and James B. Angell. Other portions of the collection include lectures, publications, and topical files relating to professional affiliations and the University of Michigan School of Education. There are also some photographs and papers of L. Elizabeth Reed Dunham relating to her organizational activities.
Subjects:
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Classical philology.; Dennison, Walter, 1869-1917.; Drake, Joseph H. (Joseph Horace), 1860-1947.; Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), 1858-1927.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Education.; University of Michigan--Student notebooks.; Wenley, R. M. (Robert Mark), 1861-1929.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Europe.; Travel.
Contributors:
Dunham, Elizabeth Reed.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Snapshots.
- Background information
  - Biographical materials, personnel reports, salary appointments, and clippings (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1906-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1930 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
  - January 1943 (Box 1)
  - February 1943 (Box 1)
  - March-April 1943 (Box 1)
  - May-December 1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - January-June, 1948 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1948 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1949 (Box 1)
  - June-December 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960-1970 (Box 1)
- Student notebooks
  - Philosophy I. Professor Robert M. Wenley 1905 (Box 1)
  - Roman Art I and II. Professor Francis W. Kelsey 1906 (Box 1)
  - Philosophy: Plato. Professor Charles Vibbert 1906 (Box 1)
  - Development of the Roman Constitution. Professor Joseph Drake 1906 (Box 1)
  - Latin Style. 1907 (Box 1)
  - Roman Political Institutions. Professor Joseph Drake 1907 (Box 1)
  - Public International Law. Professor James B. Angell (Box 1)
  - Latin Inscriptions. Professor Walter Dennison (Box 1)
  - Private Life of the Romans. Prof. Walter Dennison (Box 1)
  - European History. Professor Earle Dow (Box 1)
  - Aristotle. Professor Sellars (Box 1)
  - Greek Art. Professor Fairbanks (Box 1)
  - International Law. (Box 1)
- Lectures and unpublished works
  - Miscellaneous 1934-1968 (Box 1)
- Topical files
  - American Classical League 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Civitas Romana 1912-1914 (Box 1)
  - Classical Association of the Middle West and South
    - General 1940-1960 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence 1942-1957 (Box 1)
  - Course Evaluations 1932-1946 (Box 1)
  - Local groups 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Payne-Hinsdale Awards 1938-1949 (Box 1)
  - School of Education
    - Administrative Committee 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Executive Committee 1957-1979 (Box 2)
    - Faculty meetings 1949-1964 (Box 2)
    - Report of the secretary of the faculty 1948-1960 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Annuitants Association 1953-1968 (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Conference programs 1939-1954 (Box 2)
  - Publications
    - 1930-1938 (Box 2)
    - 1941-1945 (Box 2)
    - 1946-1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949-1957 (Box 2)
  - The Language of the Ages 1939 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. L. Elizabeth Dunham papers
    - American Association of University Women 1941-1960 (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan Alumni Association 1956-1957 (Box 2)
  - Photographs: snapshots of trips to Europe and the western United States, 4 envelopes (Box 2)